Software Engineer

BRANT COLLINS

Phone: (219) 331-1541

Email: mailto:lbrantcollins@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/brant-collins

Github: Ibrantcollins.github.io

Profile

Software engineer, statistician, and teacher. As a software engineer, enjoy leveraging experience as a statistician and teacher by working in organizations that value input from their technologists about varied aspects of their digital products. Work best surrounded by smart people who generously share ideas.

Skills

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Intermediate proficiency: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js and express, MVC with REST, React, Python with Flask, Ruby with Sinatra, mongoDB, SQL, Git, GitHub, and Agile workflow

R, C, SAS, vi, LaTeX, markdown SOFT SKILLS

Public speaking, professional writing

Education

PHD in STATISTICS
University of Chicago
BS in MATHEMATICS
University of Texas at San Antonio

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW

General Assembly, Chicago

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW – General Assembly, Chicago, 2019-present General Assembly is a global leader in technology education

- Programming: Designed and built web applications using Javascript, JQuery, HTML, and CSS.
- **Web development**: Designed and built full-stack applications using Javascript, Express with Node.js, React, Python with Flask, Ruby with Sinatra, noSQL and SQL databases
- Version control: git and Github

SENIOR LECTURER IN STATISTICS – University of Chicago, 2003-2009, 2012-2019 University of Chicago is a top-tier research institution with a top-five statistics graduate studies program

- **Teaching**: Taught statistics to 2500+ diverse, high-achieving undergraduates.
- Training: Held workshops for 800+ students new to R and RMarkdown
- Mentoring: Guided new lecturers and graduate student instructors.
- Advising: Offered course and degree plan advising to statistics majors, minors, and non-majors.
- Data analysis: Programmed in R, C, and SAS. Wrote reports using LaTeX and Markdown.

RESEARCHER AND STATISTICIAN – Chapin Hall at the University of Chicago, 2009-2012 Chapin Hall is a research and policy think tank for issues relating to the welfare of children and families

- **Risk analysis**: Wrote SQL queries and SAS programs to analyze and present data for researchers and policy makers regarding the experiences of over 1.5 million children in foster care in 26 states.
- **Professional writing**: Co-authored or contributed to the methodology sections of white papers, policy proposals, and peer-reviewed research.
- **Public speaking**: Delivered talks on statistical analyses and their results to technical and non-technical audiences of sizes 10 to 300.

Other Tech Interests

Collins family tech guru: Act as the family tech help desk -- building desktops, doing complete tear-downs of laptops to replace that noisy fan or cracked screen, advising on tech purchases, etc.